

APPLIED MATHEMATICS UNDERGRADUATE · DEEP LEARNING ENTHUSIAS

770, Radhakrishnan Bhawan, IIT Roorkee, Roorkee-247667, Uttarakhand, India

🛮 🕻 (+91) 9650788548 | 🗷 aagarwal@ma.iitr.ac.in | 🖸 aniket-agarwal1999 | 🛅 aniket-agarwal1999 | 💆 agarwalaniket11

Interests_

My research interest domain mainly lies in the broader fields of Computer Vision and Natural Language Processing and their applications. I have a special interest in the field of Generative models and Graph networks along with making models robust and immune to adversarial examples. I am deeply interested in learning more about the theoretical aspects behind deep learning in general.

Education.

Indian Institute of Technology Roorkee

Roorkee, India

July 2017-Present

INTEGRATED MSc APPLIED MATHEMATICS

• Cumulative Grade Point, CGPA:7.71/10

New Delhi. India

March 2015-March 2017

Maharaja Agrasen Model School

PCM(ALONG WITH COMPUTER SCIENCE)

• Percentage:94.8%

Publications

RelTransformer: Balancing the Visual Relationship Detection from LocalContext, Scene and Memory

Jun Chen, **Aniket Agarwal**, Sherif Abdelkarim, Deyao Zhu, Mohamed Elhoseiny

- · Under Review
- ArXiv Preprint: [Link]

Exploring Long Tail Visual Relationship Recognition at Scale

Aniket Agarwal*, Sherif Abdelkarim*, Panos Achlioptas, Jun Chen, Jiaji Huang, Boyang Li, Kenneth Church,

MOHAMED ELHOSEINY

- The paper is accepted for ICCV 2021
- ArXiv Preprint: [Link]

Visual Relationship Detection using Scene Graphs: A Survey

ANIKET AGARWAL*, AYUSH MANGAL*, VIPUL*

- The paper is under review in ACM CSUR journal
- ArXiv Preprint: [Link]

Revisiting CycleGAN for semi-supervised segmentation

Arnab Mondal, **Aniket Agarwal**, Jose Dolz, Christian Desrosiers

• ArXiv Preprint: [Link]

Research Experience

Research Project with NUS CVML group

Singapore

Under the supervision of Prof Angela Yao, NUS

Jun 2021 - Present

- Working on the task of 3D action recognition using various modalities such as depth map, joint information, etc.
- Specifically targetting on the problem of hand-action recognition, along with the pose estimation.

Research Collaboration with CAIR group, KAUST

Saudi Arabia May 2020 - Feb 2021

UNDER THE SUPERVISION OF PROF MOHAMED ELHOSEINY

- Developing a new Scene Graph Generation technique to get a more unbiased result by solving the problem of long-tail of infrequent relationships in datasets.
- Specifically developing further upon the ideas set up by paper 'Long-tail Visual Relationship Recognition with a Visiolinguistic Hubless Loss' for long-tail visual relationship detection.
- A paper of the work done for the same is also currently under review for ICCV 2021.

Research Project on Steerable Networks

Montreal, Canada

Under the supervision of Arnab K. Mondal, PhD McGill University

July 2020 - Sep 2020

- Developing upon the ideas presented in the paper 'General E(2)-Equivariant Steerable CNNs'.
- The main target is to adapt this framework for other downstream tasks such as image translation, super-resolution, etc. by exploiting the learning capacity of steerable networks.

Research Project with LIVIA group, ETS Montreal

Montreal, Canada

Under the supervision of Prof Jose Dolz and Prof Christian Desrosiers, ETS Montreal

May 2019 - July 2019

- Developed a new training procedure for semi-supervised segmentation using normal losses along with adversarial ones, with ideas inspired
 from CycleGAN model [GitHub Link].
- The model was thoroughly tested and experimented on various normal context and medical datasets.

Research project on medical image segmentation

Roorkee, India

Under the supervision of r. balasubramanian, professor, computer science department, iit roorkee

August 2018 - March 2019

- Using clustering algorithms to segment out the affected region in the case of skin cancer and brain stroke.
- To further improve the results, various evolutionary algorithms like Genetic Algorithms, Particle Swarm Optimization and Whale Optimization were used along with usage of certain encryption techniques to maintain user privacy.

Projects _

vGraph: A Generative model for joint community detection and node representational learning

Roorkee, India

Under NeurIPS Reproducibility Challenge

October 2019 - November 2019

- Implementing the paper along with reproducing the experiments and baselines reported in the paper under NeurIPS reproducibility challenge 2019
- · Github Repo: Link

Papers We Read Roorkee, India

Under Vision and Language Group

September 2019 - Present

- Core Contributor to the repo containing summaries of the various papers that we as a group have discussed
- Github Repo: Link

LEDNet Roorkee, India

SELF-INTEREST PROJECT May 2019

- $\bullet \ \ \text{Implementation of LEDNet} \ \text{architecture in pytorch, a model for semantic segmentation with very few parameters}$
- Github Repo: Link

LeDoc Roorkee, India

SELECTED FOR INTER IIT TECH MEET, 2018 HELD IN IIT BOMBAY

December 2018

- This is a project aimed to assist doctors in preliminary stages of Medical Image Analysis
- The main purpose of the app is to segment out the affected region and also determine the severity of the disease
- Github Repo: Link

Achievements & Scholarships ____

2018	Participation, Inter IIT Tech Meet in Engineer's Conclave Event	Mumbai, India
2018	Scholarship, Inspire Scholarship Fellow under the Ministry of Science and Technology	Roorkee, India
2018	All India Rank 49, In Amex Analyze This 2018 (among the 800 participated teams)	Roorkee, India
2018	Dedicated Member Award , Awarded Dedicated member award by NSS, IIT Roorkee for my excellent work	Roorkee, India
2017	All India Rank 4605, Joint Entrance Exam Advanced(among 150,000 candidates)	India

Extracurricular Activity

Vision and Language Group

Roorkee. India

CO-President Oct 2018-PRESENT

- We conduct various open sessions for paper discussions on recent papers accepted in various ML/CV/NLP related conferences
- We also take up research projects on in collaboration with Professors from various universities with the aim of publication in various DL/CV/NLP conferences.
- Website: [Link]

ACM IIT Roorkee Chapter

Roorkee, India

Treasurer April 2019-PRESENT

We are a bunch of Computer Science enthusiasts aiming at fostering a culture of research in the field of Theoretical Computer Science and its
applications in various fields

August 10, 2021 Aniket Agarwal · Résumé 2

Academic Reinforcement Programme

Roorkee, India

UGTA мемвеr *Aug 2018-Nov 2018*

• Served as a Teaching Assistant for MAN-001 course taught to the freshmen batch

NSS IIT ROORKEE Roorkee, India

EDITORIAL TEAM MEMBER Aug 2017-May 2018

· Organized various events like Swachh Bharat Abhiyaan, Cloth distribution drives and encouraged people towards the advantages of the same

References_

Prof Mohamed Elhoseiny

Saudi Arabia

ASSISTANT PROFESSOR, KING ABDULLAH UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY(KAUST), SAUDI ARABIA

• Email: mohamed.elhoseiny@kaust.edu.sa

Prof Christian Desrosiers

Montreal, Canada

Professor, École de Technologie Supérieure (ETS), montreal

• Email: christian.desrosiers@etsmtl.ca

Prof Jose Dolz

Montreal, Canada

Assistant Professor, École de Technologie Supérieure (ETS), montreal

• Email: jose.dolz@etsmtl.ca

Prof R. Balasubramanian Roorkee, India

PROFESSOR, DEPT. OF COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING, IIT ROORKEE

• Email: balarfma@iitr.ac.in

Arnab K. Mondal Montreal, Canada

PHD CANDIDATE, McGILL UNIVERSITY
• Email: arnabm@cim.mcgill.ca